In 2020, the Nobel Peace Prize was awarded to the World Food Programme (WFP).
2020年，诺贝尔和平奖授予了世界粮食计划署（WFP）。
Why a Nobel Prize for the WFP, and why now?
诺贝尔奖为何颁给世界粮食计划署？又为何是现在？
In 2019, the WFP assisted nearly 100 million people in 88 countries.
2019年，世界粮食计划署为88个国家的近1亿人提供了援助。
It is the safety net for those who fall off the edge of existence.
对那些从生存边缘跌落的人来说，它就是安全网。
It is a response to the problem of food instability.
它是应对粮食不稳定问题的一种举措。
Its Nobel Prize reminds us all of the moral hazard in imagining that the poor and vulnerable are somebody else’s problem.
它荣获诺贝尔奖，提醒我们所有人：以为穷人和弱势群体是别人的问题，这种想法隐含着道德风险。
The WFP has been around since 1961 and has been the global coordinator of nationally based efforts to avoid disasters with food aid.
世界粮食计划署自1961年起就已存在，一直担任全球协调者，统筹各国借助粮食援助避免灾难的行动。
Despite decades of effort to eliminate hunger, the latest estimate is that about 11% of people on the planet (about 820 million people) are suffering daily undernourishment.
尽管消除饥饿的努力已持续了数十年，但据最新估计，地球上约11%的人（约8.2亿人）每天都在忍受营养不良。
Progress in reducing undernourishment has stopped despite gains through the 1990s and 2000s.
尽管整个20世纪90年代和21世纪头十年都曾取得成效，但减少营养不良的进展已经停滞。
Developed countries sometimes offer food and aid to developing ones, but at a price.
发达国家有时会向发展中国家提供粮食和援助，但这是有代价的。
One American philosopher stated that addressing the needs of the poor and vulnerable is about more than money—it is mostly about creating conditions under which prosperity and opportunity can thrive.
一位美国哲学家曾表示，满足穷人和弱势群体的需求不只关乎金钱——更主要的是创造条件，让繁荣与机遇得以蓬勃发展。
When aid is offered with heavy conditions attached, like loan repayment or food for resources, it often widens the gap between rich and poor and sustains the old world order.
如果提供援助时附带苛刻的条件，比如偿还贷款或以资源换粮食，这种援助往往会扩大贫富差距，维系旧的世界秩序。
This is why the work of the WFP is so vital.
正因如此，世界粮食计划署的工作才如此重要。
The scientific community, however, can provide a helping hand to the WFP.
不过，科学界可以向世界粮食计划署伸出援手。
By sharing knowledge of agriculture and climate with peers in countries most vulnerable to poverty and hunger, scientists can help reduce these problems.
科学家可以通过与最易陷入贫困和饥饿国家的同行分享农业和气候知识，帮助缓解这些问题。
By making its voice heard, science can lead by example.
科学发出自己的声音，便能以身作则。
The ability to overcome food shortages that must be built into some of the poorest countries will not come from loans from wealthy countries, which may have food problems of their own, or world economic institutions.
一些最贫穷的国家必须建立起战胜粮食短缺的能力，而这种能力既不会来自富裕国家的贷款——它们自身可能也存在粮食问题——也不会来自世界经济机构。
This ability will be built upon self-confident people using open and shared scientific knowledge to pull themselves out of their misery.
这种能力将建立在这样的基础上：充满自信的人们运用开放、共享的科学知识，让自己摆脱苦难。